<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Micros on Flirting With Neutrality</title><link>https://pborocz.github.io/micro/</link><description>Recent content in Micros on Flirting With Neutrality</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>peter.borocz@gmail.com (Péter Böröcz)</managingEditor><webMaster>peter.borocz@gmail.com (Péter Böröcz)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 10:12:14 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pborocz.github.io/micro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Accrual vs. Cash Accounting in Federal Spending Discourse</title><link>https://pborocz.github.io/micro/accrual_vs_cash_govt/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 10:12:14 -0700</pubDate><author>peter.borocz@gmail.com (Péter Böröcz)</author><guid>https://pborocz.github.io/micro/accrual_vs_cash_govt/</guid><description>While not an accountant, I believe I can distinguish between cash vs. accrual accounting, pertinently:
Accrual accounting recognises either the obligation or intent of the government to spend
money (or the converse) on a planned basis. Cash accounting tracks the actual cash movements. [Please correct me if there&amp;rsquo;s anything pertinently wrong about this characterisation!]
From this, we can distinguish several salient points:
Legislative Spending is an Accrual Basis Concept Legislation that stipulates (future) spending should be treated on an accrual basis, programs</description></item><item><title>"New on New"</title><link>https://pborocz.github.io/micro/new_on_new/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 16:17:28 -0700</pubDate><author>peter.borocz@gmail.com (Péter Böröcz)</author><guid>https://pborocz.github.io/micro/new_on_new/</guid><description>What is it? When combining more than one new resource with another one.
Resources could be almost anything, i.e. people, technology, processes etc.
What are some examples? Pairing a brand new technology stack on a brand-new project (particularly without adequate risk-management). Pairing a newly-hired employee under a newly-hired supervisor/manager. Pairing a brand new project manager onto a new, high-risk project. Suggestions? As a risk manager, I always suggest never getting into the New on New scenario.</description></item></channel></rss>